[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133befb", "question": "What New York Giants' bone-crushing tackle in 1985 ended quarterback Joe Thiemann's career?", "answer": "Lawrence Taylor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf1", "question": "In which city's harbor would you find the statue of The Little Mermaid?", "answer": "Copenhagen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a095", "question": "What was the name of Punky Brewster's dog?", "answer": "Brandon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c1", "question": "On what sitcom was a combination of milk and Pepsi the preferred refreshment for one of the lead characters?", "answer": "Laverne and Shirley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd0", "question": "The goddess Athena was responsible for causing whose hair to turn into snakes?", "answer": "Medusa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ca3da444f0f6af5b06663d", "question": "In which Dickens novel does the character Fezziwigs appear?", "answer": "A Christmas Carol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6a", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Ray\"?", "answer": "Jamie Foxx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab39", "question": "Belgrade lies on the Danube and which other river?", "answer": "Sava", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133981d", "question": "Who provided the voice for Mister Swackhammer, the main antagonist in the movie Space Jam?", "answer": "Danny DeVito", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c37", "question": "What is the name of the theme song from the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "I'll Be There For You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b596", "question": "Which building has been nicknamed \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "GE Building", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323244bf195a31e15d738e", "question": "What year did George Eliot publish her novel \"Daniel Deronda\"?", "answer": "1876", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b763", "question": "In soccer, how many yellow cards result in a red card?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c78ffbde8045e48466c4", "question": "What is the only mammal native to Iceland?", "answer": "Artic fox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a1e1d75b5a031299b74573b", "question": "The Okapi is native to which African country?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19c", "question": "What dog breed was the official 1972 Summer Olympics mascot?", "answer": "Dachshund", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2bc", "question": "What are the three main types of sugar?", "answer": "Glucose, fructose and sucrose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd21", "question": "What company originally owned the name \"Saltine\" before losing it to trademark dilution?", "answer": "Nabisco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1e78b5a031299b745740", "question": "What year did Great Britain claim the eastern half of Australia?", "answer": "1770", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe12ecee39efa6330e0fed4", "question": "Which country has the largest rhino population?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133956b", "question": "What was wrong with the Grinch's heart in, How the Grinch Stole Christmas?", "answer": "It was two sizes too small", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa73", "question": "What US State flag has a Union Jack Flag on it?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b164", "question": "What does the letter F stand for in JFK's name?", "answer": "Fitzgerald", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa94", "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian province Nova Scotia?", "answer": "Halifax", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de3", "question": "For what movie did director Fritz Lang himself dub the whistling for star Peter Lorre?", "answer": "M", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b176", "question": "In what year did the State of California officially join the United States as its 31st state?", "answer": "1850", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb08", "question": "What newspaper was founded in 1889 by Charles H. Dow and Edward Jones?", "answer": "Wall Street Journal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b580", "question": "What year was the first iPhone released?", "answer": "2007", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70c", "question": "In the Christmas song, The Holly and The Ivy which one bears the crown?", "answer": "The holly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe93b956bd93ce3a4e5f6a5", "question": "Who was the first to accurately describe the human circulatory system?", "answer": "William Harvey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339689", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Mr. Burns' stuffed bear?", "answer": "Bobo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f95b02755722f97b22684db", "question": "What does Dumbledore give to Ron in his will?", "answer": "Deluminator", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef669f6ce05a3942286e7a", "question": "How many of the original three Star Wars films did George Lucas direct?", "answer": "One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be74", "question": "Who were the winners of the James E. Sullivan Award for amateur athletics in 1986 and 1988?", "answer": "Jackie Joyner-Kersee and Florence Griffith-Joyner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a979", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Eduskunta?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943d", "question": "What 2000 movie depicts the war on drugs in Ohio, California and Mexico?", "answer": "Traffic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd3", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Hippomenes also known as?", "answer": "Melanion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ba", "question": "What actor played the role of Jack Horner in the movie \"Boogie Nights\"?", "answer": "Burt Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901da79709c1c34536e6eaf", "question": "In ice hockey, how many players for each team are allowed on the ice at the same time?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133972a", "question": "Who played weatherman Phil Connors in the movie \"Groundhog Day\"?", "answer": "Bill Murray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a0", "question": "What\u2019s the name of the science of growing plants in liquid nutrients instead of soil?", "answer": "Hydroponics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2118231a458464a93c443", "question": "What word describes the act of marking a document in red?", "answer": "Rubrication", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b4b101dd7bf43be5e7c5", "question": "What's the age limit for horses competing in the Kentucky Derby?", "answer": "3-years-old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b8", "question": "What is the largest cat in the America's?", "answer": "Jaguar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91b", "question": "What does the abbreviation \"AT&T\" stand for?", "answer": "American Telephone and Telegraph Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0e184fcbed638185eaa1b", "question": "What three countries intersect at Mount Roraima?", "answer": "Venezuela, Brazil, and Guyana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b7ffb733a3a814d89068c65", "question": "Who wanted you to \"Shake Your Groove Thing\"?", "answer": "Peaches & Herb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f6e", "question": "What vehicle was driven by Fred Jones?", "answer": "The Mystery Machine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3845815febcc896f927d", "question": "What is the first sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Aries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c7ebfbde8045e48466ca", "question": "What Australian marsupial is often mistaken for a monkey?", "answer": "Cuscus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338938", "question": "What did Fender name the follow up to their \"Telecaster\" guitar?", "answer": "Stratocaster", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594a64142ebb971c1417fba0", "question": "The song \"I Talk to the Trees\" comes from what musical?", "answer": "Paint Your Wagon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef65486ce05a3942286e6b", "question": "Who directed the film \"The Usual Suspects\"?", "answer": "Bryan Singer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a938", "question": "What is the 3 letter code for O'Hare International Airport?", "answer": "ORD", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c8a48b90aac110e416706c", "question": "Zymology, also known as zymurgy, is the study of what?", "answer": "Fermentation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a3c83c4039f3d7859290ffb", "question": "In the TV Show \"Gunsmoke\", who portrayed deputy Chester Goode?", "answer": "Dennis Weaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9952ebfabb9c85d8a971", "question": "Eirene was the Greek goddess of what?", "answer": "Peace", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4c", "question": "What sign are you if you were born on Valentine\u2019s Day?", "answer": "Aquarius", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b53", "question": "Cate Blanchett received an Oscar nomination in 2008 for portraying what male musician?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea6", "question": "What hobby uses the Yoshizawa-Randlett diagramming system?", "answer": "Origami", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b5", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the three-eyed fish named?", "answer": "Blinky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc6beec223966ae8f8887", "question": "What is Neo's official name in the film \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Anthony A. Anderson, which is why Agent Smith refers to him as \"Mr. Anderson\".", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba51e874c93a3298b214c", "question": "What country is credited with inventing the modern, self-igniting match?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5cb", "question": "The Pathfinder spacecraft landed on what planet in 1997?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66092a5bfecdd737e0835", "question": "How many Earths could fit in the Sun?", "answer": "1.3 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe9", "question": "Oil wrestling is the national sport of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1f", "question": "What everyday item did John Walker invent?", "answer": "Friction matches", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d116054fea7fe947a2226c", "question": "What group of natural pigments affects the color of the hair and skin?", "answer": "Melanin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff7bfb32b316f4693fb6794", "question": "The singer of which song also voiced Frosted Flakes\u2019 Tony the Tiger?", "answer": "Thurl Ravenscroft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049cd4cf93664eb10486aa", "question": "What is the name of the avenue that lies between 12th and 14th Avenue in San Francisco?", "answer": "Funston Avenue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d6", "question": "Tommy Lee Jones and Al Gore were roommates at what university?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c776", "question": "What type of animal flew to space in the US V2 rocket launched in 1949?", "answer": "A monkey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a728cdf6bcd28c11938328d", "question": "What was used for blood in Hitchcock's \"Psycho\"?", "answer": "Chocolate syrup", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c638", "question": "What is the worlds fastest growing plant?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934e", "question": "Who played Alex's sister, Mallory, on the TV show \"Family Ties\"?", "answer": "Justine Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd1", "question": "Who are the Glimmer Twins?", "answer": "Mick Jagger and Keith Richards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04a", "question": "Gene, Louise, Tina, Bob, and Linda are the main characters of which animated sitcom?", "answer": "Bob's Burgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a61", "question": "Whose wife could eat no lean?", "answer": "Jack Sprat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f1676af7c52aae91cc07b9", "question": "The Republic of Guinea-Bissau is located on which African coast?", "answer": "Western coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b432", "question": "What year did the Mau Mau Uprising start?", "answer": "1952", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b3232b9bf195a31e15d7393", "question": "What are you doing if you are shucking an oyster?", "answer": "Opening it", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc8a", "question": "What must be manufactured by Victorinox or Wenger to be official?", "answer": "Swiss Army knives", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd661f6a5bfecdd737e0840", "question": "What country has hosted the most Olympics?", "answer": "USA", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f839fe83fe1f2a824c2a", "question": "The \"St. Valentine's Day Massacre\" was perpetrated by which historical figure?", "answer": "Al Capone ordered the murders on February 14, 1929, but the primary target got away.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba694874c93a3298b2159", "question": "What is the sixth planet from the Sun?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339444", "question": "Who played Edward in the movie \"Edward Scissorhands\"?", "answer": "Johnny Depp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c4", "question": "The word gherkin, a small pickle, is based on the Dutch word \"gurken\" meaning what?", "answer": "Cucumbers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e2", "question": "How did Buffalo Bill die?", "answer": "Kidney failure", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062a58c9d816e292245c17", "question": "What is Judy Chicago's most well-known work?", "answer": "Regarded as the first epic feminist artwork, \"The Dinner Party\" functions as a symbolic history of women in Western civilization.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4c3b49076251badbead0", "question": "Which First Lady was the first to graduate college?", "answer": "Lucy Hayes -- The wife of President Rutherford B. Hayes, she received her degree from Wesleyan Female College at the age of 18.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4af", "question": "At what nation does Panama attach onto South America?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc5", "question": "Which detective story writer created the character Tuppence Beresford?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a1ea20565ad31a57c7a9", "question": "Which US president had a mockingbird he carried on his shoulder?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339041", "question": "Which is the only book published by Margaret Mitchell during her lifetime?", "answer": "Gone with the Wind", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6574bae7e414034b5aedb", "question": "Where did Barack Obama teach constitutional law?", "answer": "University of Chicago", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93e", "question": "What was the only nation to qualify for all 16 soccer World Cups in the 20th century?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdaffe65ff7d326b622a5e", "question": "What country's entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339809", "question": "What Norwegian pop band included Morten, Pal & Mags?", "answer": "A Ha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339533", "question": "Who was Larry Sanders' sidekick on \"The Larry Sanders Show\"?", "answer": "Hank Kingsley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e74", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"City Lights\"?", "answer": "Virginia Cherrill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aacc", "question": "What city is the capital of the US state of Kansas?", "answer": "Topeka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c73b", "question": "What psychiatrist developed the principal of \"synchronicity\"?", "answer": "Carl Jung", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a852", "question": "Approximately, how many feet above the sea level is Machi Picchu located at?", "answer": "8,000", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c571", "question": "What cord or strong strand of string tissue attaches a muscle to bone?", "answer": "Tendon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e29", "question": "Whose opera \"The Tale of Tsar Saltan\" contains \"The Flight of the Bumblebee\"?", "answer": "Nikolai Rimsky-Korsakov's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339216", "question": "What fictional Kansas town is the earthly home of the young Superman?", "answer": "Smallville", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8aa1c01dd7bf43be5e757", "question": "What is the Hebrew term for \"commandment\"?", "answer": "Mitzvah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfbe", "question": "Which writer coined the word \"Cyberspace\"?", "answer": "William Gibson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdd19ec223966ae8f88fe", "question": "Which tennis player had the nickname \"The Rocket\"?", "answer": "Rod Laver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600243f74be4723ccac2219e", "question": "Which writer was the author of the 1976 book \"Roots: The Saga of an American Family\"?", "answer": "Alex Haley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f1649f3f9b80650dbe7f92b", "question": "Which country music artist was the runner-up on the 21st season of the TV show \"Survivor\"?", "answer": "Chase Rice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396dd", "question": "Which pop singer refers to her fans as \"little monsters\"?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b40906d333868d34d6de", "question": "What part of the world did the Vikings come from?", "answer": "Scandinavia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be44", "question": "What is the only fruit to be ever banned from airplanes?", "answer": "Durian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7527a9e54d890926f705", "question": "What U.S. town has a replica of the Eiffel Tower topped with a cowboy hat?", "answer": "Paris, Texas -- Paris, Tennessee and Las Vegas, Nevada also have replicas of the Eiffel Tower, albeit, without the hat.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133befc", "question": "Which African country has a domain of .tn?", "answer": "Tunisia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7cc", "question": "What is a traditional karate uniform called?", "answer": "Gi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339888", "question": "What colour was Oscar the Grouch during the first season of Sesame Street?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071d5e3745b36be73039d7", "question": "What operation brought over 1,500 German scientists, engineers and technicians following the end of World War II to the US to aid in military research?", "answer": "Operation Paperclip", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a0", "question": "Who Wrote Aretha Franklins \"Respect\"?", "answer": "Otis Redding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133987e", "question": "In Star Wars, what kind of a farm does Luke Skywalker grow up on?", "answer": "Moisture farm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f0ecff048f679a45aaab", "question": "Verminophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Germs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c416", "question": "How many horns did a triceratops have?", "answer": "Three", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fb4", "question": "What novel centres on the romances of Ursula and Gudrun Brangwen?", "answer": "Women in Love", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bf", "question": "What Pacific Ocean trench is the deepest in the world?", "answer": "Mariana trench", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ac", "question": "Moroccan stews are cooked and served in a pot called what?", "answer": "Tagine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4973ff048f679a45abb8", "question": "What part of the scientific method tests a hypothesis?", "answer": "Experiment", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b358dd55db0d66a186cb564", "question": "Where would you most often come across a chicane?", "answer": "On a motor racing track", "category": "general"}, {"id": "593c4d2db8198b9a2b07796c", "question": "Who won an Academy Award for his portrayal of Jake LaMotta in the film \"Raging Bull\"?", "answer": "Robert De Niro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e147f3f6ca6dac04a20ca53", "question": "The Harry Nilsson song \"Gotta Get Up\" was frequently used in which Netflix original series?", "answer": "Russian Doll", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee6", "question": "Who preceded Georges Pompidou as French President?", "answer": "Charles de Gaulle", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6aa4820565ad31a57c814", "question": "Who first developed stereophonic sound?", "answer": "Alan Blumlein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fff", "question": "Who wrote the best selling novel \"Polo\"?", "answer": "Jilly cooper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab8d", "question": "What country shares a border with Cambodia to the northwest?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b565", "question": "What is the most expensive spice in the world?", "answer": "Saffron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396bf", "question": "Which actor played the role of Dawson on the TV show \"Dawson's Creek\"?", "answer": "James Van Der Beek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339078", "question": "What country is Puccini's opera, \"Turandot\", set in?", "answer": "China", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34a", "question": "Which country was the setting for the TV serial \"The Flame Trees of Thika\"?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a168", "question": "What is Tina Turner's real name?", "answer": "Anne Mae Bullock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c29d", "question": "What plant is opium derived from?", "answer": "The opium poppy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d8", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "Vladimir Nabokov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb01", "question": "What is the chemical element Azote now referred to as?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad7ebfdb24f84e0b9f9ffe2", "question": "The song \"Honolulu Baby\" was written for which Laurel and Hardy film?", "answer": "Sons of the Desert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a91420565ad31a57c7fc", "question": "What Dallas nightclub did Oswald murderer Jack Ruby own?", "answer": "The Carousel Club", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e7c", "question": "Which TV show used the song \"Bad Reputation\" by Joan Jett as its theme song?", "answer": "Freaks and Geeks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96dda23c87fd04dd15e30", "question": "Who was the first U.S. Vice President to resign?", "answer": "John C. Calhoun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67c", "question": "In what US state did Leon Leonwood Bean open his first retail store?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b63ee662d71a53651004", "question": "In Herman Melville\u2019s novel \"Moby Dick\", who was the loyal, reasonable first mate?", "answer": "Starbuck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b2", "question": "What town is Oklahoma State University located in?", "answer": "Stillwater", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339318", "question": "What dance did Chunk had to perform to gain access to Mikey's house in the 1985 movie \"The Goonies\"?", "answer": "The Truffle Shuffle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4a4349076251badbeab2", "question": "What holiday commemorates the day the last slaves were freed in Texas?", "answer": "Juneteenth -- It commemorates the day (June 19, 1865) that slaves in Galveston, Texas learned that they were free.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592ead7df83302ff91e4647d", "question": "What was a Portuguese moidore?", "answer": "A gold coin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a5e", "question": "What 1977 ballad by Debby Boone was the #1 song of the 1970's, according to Billboard magazine?", "answer": "You Light Up My Life", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fed2598ec223966ae8f8907", "question": "A \"foo fighter\", upon which the famous 1990's band is named, is a term derived from which line of professionals?", "answer": "Aircraft Pilots", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9a2cebfabb9c85d8a978", "question": "Which British Prime Minister died in 1965?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae59", "question": "How many transatlantic trips did the Titanic make before sinking?", "answer": "None", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc0", "question": "What is the \"Big Mac\" that was built in Michigan in 1957?", "answer": "The Mackinac Bridge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ef", "question": "Fear of the color white is known as what?", "answer": "Leukophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c186", "question": "What is the fear of sunlight called?", "answer": "Heliophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b3dc01dd7bf43be5e7b6", "question": "What city created a new beachfront when it hosted the Olympics?", "answer": "Barcelona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a903", "question": "What major river runs through the city of London?", "answer": "Thames", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f5", "question": "What was the name of Ross' monkey in the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Marcel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a87", "question": "What author wrote \"The Murders in the Rue Morgue\" short story?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067a4dff9c0647b50a8057", "question": "What country hosted the 2016 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ec", "question": "What is the fourth letter of the Greek alphabet?", "answer": "Delta", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c921", "question": "What is a group of Sparrows called?", "answer": "Host", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd6", "question": "What TV show did \"Diagnosis Murder\" spin off from?", "answer": "Jake and the Fatman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b6991e1e762b54eb9be941e", "question": "What famous statue was discovered in 1820 on the Greek island of Milos?", "answer": "Venus de Milo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe65847ae7e414034b5aeeb", "question": "How many people survived the sinking of the Titanic?", "answer": "706", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596df8ccf0cc2631d16a3c63", "question": "Crazy Horse and Sitting Bull were born in which US state?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4d0", "question": "What does a \u201cseismograph\u201d measure?", "answer": "Motions of the ground", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a3346c0f9723ab15cb4b", "question": "What was Ronald Reagan\u2019s Secret Service code name?", "answer": "Rawhide", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc7", "question": "What month's birthstone places highest on the Mohs scale?", "answer": "April's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d9ae308b8581f80b092c0", "question": "While filming a segment for the show \"The Grand Tour\", what car did Richard Hammond crash in June, 2017?", "answer": "Rimac Concept One", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a4", "question": "Venice's Grand Canal ends at what huge square, the city's only piazza?", "answer": "Piazza San Marco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339532", "question": "What show featured the five orphaned Salinger siblings?", "answer": "Party of Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc3dd6ce05a3942286f28", "question": "Which member of Fleetwood Mac was inducted into the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame twice?", "answer": "Stevie Nicks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ca", "question": "What San Francisco hill is home to a famous colony of wild parrots?", "answer": "Telegraph Hill", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5eb737c95e259d786908732c", "question": "Who was the Bolshevik leader that was exiled by Joseph Stalin after Vladimir Lenin\u2019s death?", "answer": "Leon Trotsky", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a213", "question": "What cartoon, from the Talkertoon series, marked the first appearance of Betty Boop?", "answer": "Dizzy Dishes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa92473838c5c8a417f41", "question": "What material is the most expensive substance on earth?", "answer": "Antimatter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86c", "question": "What disease, caused by the bacteria Y. pestis, is spread by fleas and rats?", "answer": "Bubonic plague", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69a2420565ad31a57c750", "question": "Which Nazi fugitive did the Israelis capture in Argentina in 1960?", "answer": "Adolf Eichmann", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72a", "question": "Lake Pend Oreille is the largest lake in which US state?", "answer": "Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ea", "question": "In which Star Wars movie does Darth Vader reveal that he is Luke Skywalker's father?", "answer": "The Empire Strikes Back", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdeb", "question": "What Burlingame, California, company was founded in 1984 to provide blood and urine analysis to athletes?", "answer": "BALCO", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febac287e83c707845b20eb", "question": "What does the X in \"X-ray\" stand for?", "answer": "\"Unknown\" type of radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8a6fec223966ae8f8831", "question": "In the movie \"Polar Express\", there is one rule when it comes to hot chocolate. What is it?", "answer": "Don't let it cool", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aef7", "question": "The Gold Rush of 1849 occurred in which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb6", "question": "Who invented the spinning Jenny?", "answer": "James Hargreaves", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e2c", "question": "Who is Gwyneth Paltrow's mother?", "answer": "Blythe Danner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d118314fea7fe947a22282", "question": "Which part of the body is dermatology concerned with?", "answer": "The skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fedd9e96ce05a3942286d7e", "question": "What was the name of the girl in the film \"Jurassic Park\"?", "answer": "Lex Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc6536de0eb824d4052f7", "question": "What is the official state fruit of New Hampshire?", "answer": "Pumpkin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69aab20565ad31a57c756", "question": "In the Bible, who is the wife of Boaz?", "answer": "Ruth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c9f84fb4e2c7fbd3896751", "question": "What is champagne substituted with to turn a \u201cBlack Velvet\u201d cocktail into a \u201cPoor Man\u2019s Black Velvet\u201d cocktail?", "answer": "Cider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a504", "question": "What are the four longest rivers in the world?", "answer": "Nile, Amazon, Yangtze, Huang Ho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2b7", "question": "What is the most common reference material when measuring the Specific Gravity of a substance?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feccd1dec223966ae8f88a8", "question": "In \"Back to the Future,\" where does Doc Brown get the plutonium to power his time machine?", "answer": "Libyan terrorists", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a39", "question": "What former \"Little House on the Prairie\" star served two consecutive terms as president of the Screen Actors Guild?", "answer": "Melissa Gilbert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede2126ce05a3942286dcc", "question": "In 1996, Nintendo celebrated a milestone in the number of game cartridges sold with how many?", "answer": "One billion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f9", "question": "What is better than scissors in the paper, stone, scissors game?", "answer": "Stone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600242a54be4723ccac2218a", "question": "What nationality is author Gabriel Garcia Marquez, famed for his 1967 novel \"One Hundred Years of Solitude\"?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5989a8a3cb8751d53e7d75fc", "question": "Who won the fourth Super Bowl?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69db220565ad31a57c77a", "question": "Which American scientist devised over 100 uses for peanuts?", "answer": "George Washington Carver", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5901d8fb709c1c34536e6ea8", "question": "In what year did the Ultimate Fighting Championship start?", "answer": "1993", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be11", "question": "Fashion guru Anna Wintour is the editor of what magazine?", "answer": "Vogue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe2", "question": "According to the TV series, how many stories are there in \"The Naked City\"?", "answer": "Eight million", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d8", "question": "How many fluid ounces in a gill?", "answer": "5", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a455", "question": "Madison is the state capital of which US State situated on the Great Lakes?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f0", "question": "What company makes the Xbox console?", "answer": "Microsoft", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339180", "question": "Who was the female lead character in the movie \"Three Colors: Blue\"?", "answer": "Juliette Binoche", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac1", "question": "Into what ocean does the Zambezi River flow?", "answer": "Indian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a878", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Carnaby Street\"?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f8", "question": "Who played Wilhelmina Slater on the sitcom \"Ugly Betty\"?", "answer": "Vanessa Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b9bd364247bf200fb890", "question": "What kind of bones once stiffened corsets?", "answer": "Whale", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b32337bbf195a31e15d739b", "question": "Botswana is landlocked by which four countries?", "answer": "South Africa, Namibia, Zimbabwe, and Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a867", "question": "Montenegro's coastline lies on which sea?", "answer": "Adriatic Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b927", "question": "What were ivories to an old west gambler?", "answer": "Dice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdff4ab668d7dfe168b5b6", "question": "What were the dolls in the novel \"Valley of the Dolls\"?", "answer": "Pills/Drugs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de2", "question": "What \"Desperate Housewives\" creator broke into TV as a personal assistant to actress Dixie Carter?", "answer": "Marc Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba5a", "question": "Where did Chicago Bears standout Brian Urlacher play college football?", "answer": "University of New Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a94720565ad31a57c800", "question": "What was the name of the outlaw gang in Tombstone, Arizona that was Wyatt Earp's arch enemy?", "answer": "Cochise County Cowboys", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c610", "question": "The first four of Jupiter's Moons that were discovered, are referred to as what?", "answer": "The Galilean Moons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b9", "question": "What instrument did Don Henley play as a member of Eagles?", "answer": "Drums", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e38d36bf6c8a670a7957c5a", "question": "The United States shares a land border with how many countries?", "answer": "Two", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59bb29c1c9bff04efae6d759", "question": "Whose novels include \"The Joy Luck Club\" and \"The Kitchen God's Wife\"?", "answer": "Amy Tan's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe377bb0ada16518afdc04b", "question": "After giving up mural painting, Gustav Klimt designed for what industry?", "answer": "Fashion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133981a", "question": "Who was James Cameron's first choice to compose the music for the movie \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "Enya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a6c890aac110e4167080", "question": "How many milliliters is a teaspoon?", "answer": "5 mL", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c92", "question": "What TV show takes place in the fictional city of Orbit City?", "answer": "The Jetsons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b036", "question": "In what year did Pac-\u00adMan make its US debut?", "answer": "1980", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b0e93c964118b2bb3809cb", "question": "St. Dwynwen is the patron saint of lovers in which European country?", "answer": "Wales", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b48e", "question": "Which continent was host to the 1992 Summer and Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Europe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf8", "question": "In which movie did Neve Campbell portray a witch?", "answer": "The Craft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e83", "question": "Who first appeared in the 1939 children's book \"Cecily G and the Nine Monkeys\"?", "answer": "Curious George", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339981", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who does Homer consider to be his best friend?", "answer": "Barney Gumble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd1", "question": "On what golf course would you find the three tricky holes called the \"Amen Corner\"?", "answer": "Augusta National Golf Club", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a283", "question": "Queen provided the soundtrack to which 1980 space opera starring Max von Sydow and Brian Blessed?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdffcd51cf6db9ac4808d04", "question": "Which flag becomes the flag of Poland when turned upside down?", "answer": "Indonesia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922c", "question": "What New York City night spot was the subject of a 1984 Richard Gere movie?", "answer": "The Cotton Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa3", "question": "What do the Plastics call their \"slam book\" in the 2004 movie \"Mean Girls\"?", "answer": "The Burn Book", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feccdefec223966ae8f88ae", "question": "In which movie did 007 first utter the iconic phrase: \"Bond ... James Bond\"?", "answer": "\"Dr. No\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339717", "question": "Which 1995 movie stars Susan Sarandon and Sean Penn?", "answer": "Dead Man Walking", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c561", "question": "What is the only muscle in the human body not attached at both ends?", "answer": "Tongue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983f", "question": "Who was the first winner of the TV show \"America's Next Top Model\"?", "answer": "Adrianne Curry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0dd94fcbed638185eaa0f", "question": "How many independent city-states were there in the world in 2020?", "answer": "Three", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a856", "question": "Which building houses the world's biggest four-faced chiming clock?", "answer": "Minneapolis City Hall", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398a3", "question": "Who directed the movie \"The Passion of the Christ\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb3", "question": "Who was head coach of the Notre Dame college football team from 1918 to 1930?", "answer": "Knute Rockne", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523cf2736d4be723796b3c", "question": "What is Canada\u2019s $1 coin commonly referred to as?", "answer": "Loonie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ad4", "question": "From 1956 to 1965, Bill Cullen hosted the original version of what TV game show?", "answer": "The Price is Right", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acce", "question": "Who performed \"The Wall\" by the Berlin Wall?", "answer": "Roger Waters", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe77302eec85e375820b303", "question": "What is Antarctica's largest island?", "answer": "Alexander Island", "category": "geography"}]